Next, let's add some details to the skirt part of this set of women's clothes.
First, we continue to complete the lower part of the skirt.
We found a multidirectional tool in the creation panel tool group.
According to the belt we used before, click and draw a skirt panel according to the order.
In the process of drawing, press the left mouse button to create a straight line.
Press the control button to create a curve.
Press the release control button to create a straight line.
Finally, click the starting point to complete the closed shape.
Adjust the position of the panel in the 3D space.
Then switch back to the edit panel tool.
Select the line in the front, right-click, choose to align, and edit.
After that, the skirt panel is left and right.
Then arrange the position of the panel in the 2D window.
Then use the free powder tool to start from the front,
to the side, and create the first line.
Then sew it in the corresponding position on the belt.
After sewing, press the control button to simulate.
This panel is newly created.
Its particle diameter is the default 20 that we set.
So here we reduce the particle diameter to 8.
Reduce the conflict thickness to 1.
Then simulate to see its fold distribution.
Now we see that the whole panel may be a little wider.
So we need to make this panel a little narrower.
Use the adjustment panel tool to select the whole panel.
Then drag the selection frame of the selected panel to shrink.
After shrinking, don't forget to manually adjust the position of the panel in the 3D space.
Prevent the panel from intersecting with other panels.
Then use the edit powder line tool.
The express key is B.
Adjust the position of the seam here on the belt.
Press the control button to start the simulation.
Because of the previous creation angle,
Here we directly use the straight point.
Now if we add the edge to it directly,
This straight point is not very smooth.
We found the deep and smooth curve tool in the edit powder tool group.
Click and drag this point.
It will form a angle.
In order to make this curve a very smooth curve.
When we turn the view to the side,
We will see that there are some bones in the front.
If you want to flatten this part of the bone,
Then we need to remove this part of the bone.
So we select the point in the front and drag this point down.
Remove a small part of the panel in the middle.
Then simulate that the middle is flat.
Then we activate the belt of the seam with it.
Because of the same frozen panel as we mentioned before.
If you adjust the panel of the seam with it,
Then it may be due to the re-arrangement of the grid.
So there is an intersection with other panels.
So we reduce the particle diameter of the belt panel.
And set its level to 1.
Let it pass through the outer part of the other panels.
After the simulation is stable,
We return the level to 0.
Then we activate the skirt part of the skirt.
And simulate it together.
Here we untangle the skirt panel.
In order to prevent it from being unstable if the whole is untangled and simulated together.
After the simulation is stable,
We can choose to hide the outer panel.
Press Shift Q to hide the panel.
Then activate the inner skirt.
And then simulate it together.
After the simulation is stable,
We can freeze all the panels.
Then think about it.
Since we are going to increase the edge of the skirt panel later.
So we activate the skirt panel first.
Then use the editor panel tool to select the three edges at the same time.
Then go to the attribute editor.
Look at the total length of their 2D line.
Then we use the rectangle tool to create a single machine in the 2D window.
The width is a little more than the measurement value combination just now.
Highly according to the rectangle that you need to create.
Then we use the free-format tool to merge the sides of the two panels together.
When using the free-format tool,
Even if there is a break in the middle, it can still be selected.
Then we select these two edge panels at the same time.
Right-click to add to the side.
After adding to the side,
They have a conflict with the panel inside.
So we set its level to 1 in the attribute editor.
Let it simulate and simulate stability.
After the simulation is stable,
We will return the level to 0.
To prevent the panel from being interrupted by other errors.
Then we activate the belt panel related to them.
Simulate together.
After the simulation,
We see that the bulge in the waist is not solved.
That means it's not a bulge related to the belt.
It's related to other panels.
So we activate the other panels together to simulate.
After the simulation,
We will see that it is flat.
Then we freeze the panel.
After freezing,
Because the edge is not very obvious now.
So we can select the panel in the 2D window.
After selecting the panel,
Loosen the panel and make it wider.
In fact, this is equivalent to the length of the panel.
After adding,
Select to add to the side.
After opening the simulation,
The edge effect comes out.
After the simulation is stable,
We add the line between them.
Why choose to add after?
Because we just used the function of adding to the side.
If we create the line first.
Sometimes it may affect
We use the function of adding.
Then we switch to the free line tool.
The side of the belt close to the edge.
Smear on the belt.
The mouse is located on the line.
You can find this line according to the reference instructions.
And from the end of it.
Continue to sew to the side.
After adjusting the length.
We use the adjustment panel tool.
Select these two side panels.
Then reduce their particle diameter to 5.
Reduce the conflict thickness to 1.
Because these two panels are not very large.
So their particle diameter is reduced to 5.
Is OK.
Then Ctrl A select all panels.
Activate these panels.
Press the control key to simulate.
Then Ctrl A select all panels.
After the simulation effect is OK.
We reduce all the particle diameter to 5.
Then press the control key to simulate.
After the overall shape is satisfied.
We will start to merge the panels.
First we have to switch to the editor panel tool.
To select the line.
Then according to the blue reference point in the 3D window.
Find the two lines we want to merge.
When selecting at the same time.
Right-click to choose merge.
Because it is a left and right symmetrical panel.
So when you choose one of them.
The other line will automatically choose.
So you choose one line.
Right-click to choose merge.
It can also be merged.
If there is no symmetry.
Then you need to select two lines at the same time.
To merge them together.
These left and right symmetrical panels.
After they merge along a line.
This panel is still a left and right symmetrical panel.
That is, we often use it before.
The symmetry operation edit function.
In the process of adjustment.
It will cause the left and right of the panel to be asymmetrical.
For example, here is the sleeve.
Then we can choose one of the sleeves.
Delete it by pressing the delete button.
After deleting.
Use the adjustment panel tool.
Select the two panels of the sleeve.
Press Ctrl D.
Create a symmetrical panel.
Because the shape has been adjusted before.
So the symmetrical panel we created.
It is also adjusted.
And it is automatically generated.
So we just have to make sure.
It is placed here.
It can be placed in the correct position.
The coordinate I am using here.
Is the world coordinate.
If the coordinate you are using.
Is different from mine.
You can right-click in the 3D background.
Then in the menu bar.
Choose the coordinate.
And adjust its coordinate system.
If you find that the current panel.
The shape is not the effect you want.
Then we can freeze other panels first.
For example, I want to modify this sound.
I will freeze all other panels.
And then find the fabric of this top.
Increase the strength of its fineliner.
And increase the tension on the feet.
Make it easier to create creases.
After opening the model.
You will see it very obvious.
The whole outfit looks tight.
That's because of its stretching performance.
This is getting worse.
And there will be more obvious creases.
Finally, let's do it.
The chest pull effect.
First of all, we choose the top one.
This line.
Right click.
Choose the internal line.
And then choose the new one.
This internal line.
Choose to cut and sew.
After cutting.
The panel is no longer symmetrical.
But it doesn't matter.
We use the adjustment panel.
When choosing the tool.
Double-click center.
Open the center point.
This way, our adjustment.
It is adjusted based on the center point.
Because this panel has been widened.
The lines that are in harmony with it.
Have not been widened.
So the creases are piled up.
Produced in the front here.
Then we just need to.
Change the color of the fabric.
That's it.
This is our final.
Complete the finished effect.
See you in the next video.
Bye bye.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community